/

ABOUT

A Full Stack Application Developer with experience working as a UI, UX, & QA engineer, system administrator. Current career goals / objectives include designing and implementing enterprise-scale systems, minimizing costs / maximizing performance of software solutions, improving operational efficiency of organizations, and learning new technologies to overcome business challenges. Other professional interests include BI / analytics, data science, automation, fintech / investing.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Babson College

Application Developer

Babson Park, MA Apr 2014 – present

- I design, develop, and maintain complex, dynamic, enterprise-level web applications using Adobe ColdFusion/Fusebox, Java, PHP/Drupal, C#/.NET, JS, CSS;
- I write integrations for a variety of systems using SOAP and RESTful web services, APIs, ETL tools, MS SQL Server;
- I work with and help configure Salesforce.com (Sales/HEDA Cloud), Informatica (ICS, DI, APIs), Workday (HCM, Finance), JIRA (on prem), Cvent, SharePoint, Neoload, and other technologies.

Babson College

Software Developer Co-op / Application Developer Intern

Babson Park, MA May 2012 – Apr 2014

- Created and maintained dynamic web applications for the Babson Portal a platform of over 150 custom written tools with 2,000,000+ lines of code; researched, proposed, and integrated new software solutions;
- Wrote custom two-way web services and data feeds to integrate internal data stores and systems with a variety of third party applications and tools;
- Developed custom system workflows (XML), services, and events (JellyScript) in JIRA, performed system administration of the Atlassian stack (JIRA, Confluence) including data back-up, indexing, and restoring, system troubleshooting, patching, etc.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Advanced knowledge of Adobe ColdFusion, t-SQL, JS, CSS, XML/HTML, ETL tools (Informatica, SSIS), SOAP and RESTful web services, JIRA, Confluence.

Intermediate knowledge of C/C#, .NET, Java, PHP, Drupal, Force.com platform, SOQL/APEX/Visualforce, Workbench, git, Workday, Cvent, VSS.

Familiarity with Assembly (MASM), Python, Perl, Objective C/Swift, most flavors of shell scripting, SharePoint, Selenium, CrazyEgg, Mendix, Neoload, Laserfiche, webRTC, webVR, MEAN stack.

EDUCATION

Babson College

Babson Park, MA

F. W. Olin Graduate School of Business

Sep 2018 - Dec 2019

Master of Science in Business Analytics

Babson College

Babson Park, MA

F. W. Olin Graduate School of Business

May 2016 - Aug 2018

Master of Business Administration (MBA), Business Analytics concentration

Wentworth Institute of Technology

Boston, MA

College of Engineering and Technology

Sep 2011 – <u>Apr 2014</u>

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.82

- Dean's List (2011-2014), graduated with honors: magna cum laude
- Tau Alpha Pi Honor Society, Applied Math minor, 2014 Annual Awards Recipient
- Wentworth Community Scholarship and Wentworth Merit Scholarship Recipient

University of Tyumen (transferred out)

Tyumen, Russia

Institute of Mathematics and Computer Science

Sep 2008 - May 2011

BS/MS in Software Development and Information Systems Administration

- Full Tuition Scholarship
- 2008 Outstanding Incoming Class Award Recipient

CONFERENCES, WORKSHOPS, SEMINARS, AND HACKATHONS

- The Citizens Challenge FinTech Hackathon, Jul 2018 (Boston, MA)
- <u>Babson Finance Conference</u>, Mar 2018 (Boston, MA)
- TERMINALFOUR Advanced Web Developer, 3-day onsite training, Jan 2018 (Wellesley, MA)
- Reality Virtually Hack @ MIT, Oct 2017 (Cambridge, MA) Project: WebVR Checkout
- Programmatic Development Using Apex and Visualforce (DEV450), Sep 2017 (Boston, MA)
- Hacking for Good @ HBS, Jun 2017 (Boston, MA)
- InformaticaWorld, May 2017 (San Francisco, CA)
- HackWITus @ WIT, Mar 2017 (Boston, MA) Project: WebArm
- AT&T WebRTC Boston Coding Workshop, May 2016 (Boston, MA)
- Future of Wearables Scramble™ @ Babson, Apr 2016 (Wellesley, MA)
- Salesforce World Tour, Apr 2016, May 2017, Apr 2018 (Boston, MA)
- Boston Code Camps (24 27), Nov 2015, 2016 & Mar 2016, 2017 (Cambridge, MA)
- Workday Higher Education Summit, Oct 2015 (Wellesley, MA)
- Dyn's Hackademy, May 2015 (Manchester, NH) Project: Conversion Wars Web App
- NeoLoad 3-day training, Feb 2015 (Waltham, MA)
- <u>Laserfiche</u> 4-day training, Sep 2014 (Wellesley, MA)
- Mendix 3-day onsite training, Aug 2014
- Dyn's Hackademy, May 2014 (Manchester, NH) Project: <u>DWC Boy Scouts iOS App</u>

VADIM MANOKHIN

manokhinv.github.io

/

manokhin.vadim@gmail.com

VOLUNTEER SERVICE AND ACTIVITIES

Babson Kids on Campus Day

Babson Park, MA

Babson Garden Session Volunteer 2016 – 2018

Babson Undergraduate Commencement Babson Park, MA

Commencement Host 2016 – 2018

Babson Entrepreneurial Thought & Action (ET&A) Award Babson Park, MA

Selection Committee Member October 2016

Wentworth Admissions Office Boston, MA

Admissions Blogger Jan 2014 – Apr 2014

Wentworth Career Services Boston, MA

Web Application Developer May 2013 – Apr 2014

Wentworth International Student Services Boston, MA

International Student Ambassador Aug 2012 – Apr 2014

Wentworth President's Host Society Boston, MA

President's Host Feb 2012 – Apr 2014

- Represented the Institute at various events, on and off campus

- Served as an ambassador of public relations in various supporting roles

- Promoted Wentworth's academic programs, services and student activities

Wentworth Community Partnership

Boston, MA

Alternative Spring Break Volunteer

Mar 2012

- Focused on environmental work in the Biscayne and the Everglades National Parks, FL
- Worked with wounded birds at the Florida Keys Wild Bird Sanctuary, FL
- Worked with animals at Florida Monkey Forest Zoo, Key Largo, FL

Wentworth Counseling Center & Disability Services Partnership

Boston, MA

English II Note Taker for a Disabled Student

Oct 2011 - Dec 2011

AFFILIATIONS AND PERSONAL INTERESTS

- I've been a member of TAΠ (<u>Tau Alpha Pi</u>, Massachusetts Alpha Chapter) the professional honor society for engineering technology since 2013.
- Occasionally, I participate in the local Boston technology meetups, hackathons, and user group activities such as BNT (Boston New Technology), <u>Boston AUG</u> (Atlassian User Group), <u>Code</u> <u>for Boston</u> Hack Nights, and others.
- I am a frequent Kiva.org lender.
- I sit on the board of a local nonprofit as a Babson Board Fellow.
- Outside of my day-to-day duties as a developer I enjoy cycling, creating and playing music, learning new things, and generally expanding my horizons.